Once we've calculated an Alpha factor,
计算 Alpha 因子后
we can calculate some evaluation metrics,
我们可以计算一些评估指标
that let us compare it to other Alpha factors and get a sense for how it
这些指标使我们能够将生成的 Alpha 因子与其他 Alpha 因子进行比较
might perform when used to design a real-world portfolio.
看看使用该因子设计实际投资组合后的业绩如何
These metrics include factor returns,
这些指标包括因子收益率
sharpe ratio, information coefficient,
夏普比率 信息系数
information ratio, quantile analysis, and turnover analysis.
信息比率 分位数分析和周转率分析
We evaluate Alpha factors to help us decide whether we'll
我们会评估 Alpha 因子并判断
use them in creating a combined Alpha factor,
是否利用它们创建组合 Alpha 因子
which we'll then use within portfolio optimization.
然后在投资组合优化流程中使用组合 Alpha 因子
One useful construct, is the return of the factor,
因子的收益率是一个有用的指标
which is called the factor return.
称为因子收益率
The idea is that this is the return that a theoretical portfolio
因子收益率是指旨在利用因子呈现的套利机会
designed to capitalize on the arbitrage idea presented by the factor would produce.
获利的理论投资组合会产生的收益率
You can think of this as a way to directly measure the returns
可以将其看做权重完全由 Alpha 因子确定后
your portfolio would have if their weights were determined purely by the Alpha factor.
直接衡量投资组合收益率的方式
To calculate the factor return we create a theoretical portfolio in which the weights for
为了计算因子收益率 我们创建一个理论投资组合
each stock on each day are set equal to the Alpha value for each stock on that day.
每天每支股票的权重等于这一天每支股票的 Alpha 值
So, every day we use the prior day's known data to calculate an Alpha vector,
每一天 我们都使用前一天的已知数据计算 Alpha 因子
which we would standardize to have mean zero,
并将 Alpha 因子标准化为均值为 0
and the sum of absolute values equal to one.
绝对值之和等于 1
We use the Alpha value of each stock i,
我们使用每个股票 i 的 Alpha 值
as the weight for that stock on the current day
作为该股票在当前日期 T 的权重
T. At the end of that day we check the returns of each stock i,
在这一天结束时 我们检查每支股票 i 在这一天 T 的收益率
for that day T, which we'll call the single day return.
称为单日收益率
Then, we can calculate the weighted average of the returns,
然后计算收益率的加权平均值
using the Alpha values as weights.
并使用 Alpha 值作为权重
This gives us the factor return for a single day.
这样就会获得一天的因子收益率
We can repeat this for multiple days for a window of a year or more.
我们可以将此流程重复很多天 例如一年或更久
This time series of daily portfolio returns is the factor return.
这种每日投资组合收益率时间序列就是因子收益率
Note that we'll use historical data to calculate the factor return.
注意 我们使用历史数据计算因子收益率
So, the example of calculating this one day at a time,
这个一次计算一天收益率的示例
is to help you see that we're simulating daily portfolio decisions that are
模拟的是每日投资组合决策
only based on information that existed at the time of the theoretical trade,
并且仅基于在理论交易时存在的信息
and these portfolio decisions are refreshed every day.
这些投资组合决策每天都会更新
Notice that the factor return depends upon
注意 因子收益率取决于
the stock universe and time window of our theoretical portfolio,
理论投资组合的股票池和时间窗口
but it's a useful way to compare various Alpha factors to each
但是如果我们选择相同的股票池和时间窗口
other if we choose the same universe and time window.
我们可以对各种 Alpha 因子相互比较